landtransportguru.net 2019-12-24

# Terms of Service & Privacy Policy | Land Transport Guru

This privacy statement & terms of use covers the website www.LandTransportGuru.net (Thereafter referred to as “the Land Transport Guru website”). Please read this statement carefully before accessing our content. Your use of the Land Transport Guru website indicates your agreement to abide by the Terms in effect.

As an independent website, **Land Transport Guru bears no affiliation** with any Public Transport Operator (such as SBS Transit Ltd, SMRT Buses Ltd, Tower Transit Singapore Pte Ltd, Go Ahead Loyang Pte Ltd), nor with the Land Transport Authority (LTA) of Singapore. Any complaints or feedback regarding services provided by them should be directed to the relevant official feedback channels.

This agreement (the “Agreement”) is entered into by and between you and  **Land Transport Guru** regarding your use of the Land Transport Guru website. By using the Land Transport Guru website, you are entering into this Agreement with  **Land Transport Guru** and indicating that you agree to be bound by these terms and conditions. If you do not agree with these terms and conditions, please do not use the Service.

## Data We Collect

At Land Transport Guru, the only piece of personal information that we collect is your e-mail address, when you subscribe to our mailing list or make a comment on our website. Your e-mail address will never be disclosed to a third party company.

In addition, we use third party software, installed on the site, that collects personal and/or non personal information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. We may use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.

By setting a cookie on the Land Transport Guru website, users will not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the site’s discussion areas. We store a cookie on each user’s machine that contains a username and encrypted password. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use Land Transport Guru products or services that require you to “sign in,” and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings. However, not all Land Transport Guru services require that you accept cookies.

## 3rd party Cookies

Land Transport Guru utilises third-party software for statistics on our website usage, advertising and for social media plugin functionality. A list of these and their relevant privacy policies are listed below:

  * **Google Analytics**. We use this for general website statistics.  
<http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>
  * **Google Doubleclick for Publishers**. Land Transport Guru utilises this software for rendering its advertising. <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>
  * **Facebook**. Like buttons, and other useful plugins are used here. <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>
  * **Twitter**. Tweet buttons are loaded from Twitter. <http://twitter.com/privacy>

## Comments

In order to enhance their use of the Land Transport Guru website, users can choose to leave comments on particular articles of interest. Commenters may register anonymously. However, if a third party complains that a comment breaches our Terms of Service (e.g. libels them), then in accordance with our Terms, we will make reasonable efforts to contact the commenter and alert them to the situation. If we are required by law to disclose commenters’ contact information, we will attempt to contact commenters to give them the opportunity to respond to such requests.

We want to hear your opinions and knowledge, so please leave a comment. Occasionally we may need to remove comments from the site: either for legal reasons that could get us and you sued (e.g. contempt of court, defamation) or if a comment falls outside the realm of civilised debate (e.g. abuse, offensive or inciting hatred). Our decision is final.

## Mailing Lists

Land Transport Guru has launched a mailing list for the Land Transport Guru website, in order to provide subscribers with relevant information — breaking news, or weekly or daily round-ups, for example. In order to sign up to receive regular emails from a site’s mailing list, users must submit information including a valid email address and potentially demographic information such as location and interests. This information will be used in aggregate form only in order to assess general user interest in various internal and third party products and services, and your personal and contact information will not be passed to any other organisation.

Users who choose to sign up for a mailing list will receive regular emails from the site. Most of the time, these will be content from the site in question, but we may occasionally send out an email from a third party sponsor. This will be infrequent, and does not represent an endorsement by Land Transport Guru of any products advertised therein. It will clearly be marked as advertising: please check it out, as we hope you will feel that it is relevant to you. Since editorial independence is critical to us, you can be sure that we will never send out a sponsored email in the guise of a glowing product review. If you do not wish to receive emails from third party advertisers, please do not sign up for the mailing list.

## Third Party Links, Websites and Services

The Websites contain links to websites and content operated by third parties. Such links do not mean or imply that Land Transport Guru endorses, recommends, sponsors, or otherwise has any affiliation or relationship with any third party, and no affiliation or relationship should be presumed. Land Transport Guru does not control and is not responsible for any aspect of such websites and content.

## Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyse trends, administer the site, track user movements in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. We may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyse user movement.

## Business Transitions

In the event Land Transport Guru goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

## Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, Land Transport Guru may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on any of the Land Transport Guru website.

## Notification of Changes

Whenever Land Transport Guru changes its privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

## Contact Information

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact the editor of the Land Transport Guru site in question, or send an email to info@landtransportguru.net.

## Complaints

If you would like to complain about anything on Land Transport Guru, or any of our other assets, please email info@landtransportguru.net with the subject line ‘Complaint’.
